A Guide to the Josephine A. Dolan Collection of Nursing History 1995.0028
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
Josephine A. Dolan Collection of Nursing History
undated, 1833-1993
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
1995.0028
6.5 Linear Feet
Josephine A. Dolan was the first professor of nursing at the University of Connecticut School of Nursing. Miss Dolan collected materials to write a book on the history of nursing from dealers or, in the case of the Wolcott series, from descendants of the family.
Access
The collection is open and available for research.
Acquisition Information
Miss Dolan donated her collection to Archives & Special Collections of the University of Connecticut in 1996.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in ten series:
Series I: The Wolcott Collection (undated, 1833-1975) contains the letters of Ella Louise Wolcott (1828-1912), a descendent of the prominent Wolcott family from South Windsor, Connecticut. Handwritten and official genealogy papers of the Wolcotts are included in the collection. E. L. Wolcott's letters to her sister, Julia Wolcott Carter, and niece, Helen Kirby Dwight, are contained in the collection along with correspondence with many other family members and relatives. E. L. Wolcott suffered from a dermatological illness and spent much time in treatment at various water cures in the East. After her father died suddenly in 1858, E. L. Wolcott's financial situation deteriorated. From 1863 to 1865, E. L. Wolcott worked for the U. S. Sanitary Commission as a nurse during the Civil War. After that, E. L. Wolcott worked as a librarian in Elmira, NY, where she had been treated at the water cure establishment. The Rev. Thomas Kinnicut Beecher, brother of Harriet Beecher Stowe, was the minister at the Park Church and he and his wife Julia corresponded with E. L. Wolcott.
Series II: Civil War Nursing (undated, 1843-1901) contains a copies of letters edited by Marion Dwight, a relation of the Wolcott family, from and to E. L. Wolcott when she was a nurse during the Civil War. E. L. Wolcott's correspondence includes letters to and from Dorothea L. Dix, a pioneer in nursing prior to the establishment of trained nursing in the late 1800s. Supply and diet lists for soldiers and copies of muster rolls documenting E. L. Wolcott's service are included. Another nurse, Harriet Eaton from Maine, wrote and received letters from her family during her Civil War service and these are in the series. Photos from the Civil War, World War I and the Army Nurse Corps, as well as articles and history about the American Red Cross are part of this series.
Series III: Nursing Schools and Organizations (undated, 1873-1978) contains historical articles regarding nursing schools and organizations as well as copies of convention reports. Reports of the first seven annual conventions (1894-1900) of the American Society of Superintendents of Training Schools for Nurses are included. Historical articles concerning the Bellevue, Boston, Philadelphia and Connecticut Training Schools are found in the series. The history of the Connecticut Training School's Alumni Association, including establishment and dissolution, is chronicled in correspondence and reports.
Series IV: Nursing Leaders (1867-1995) contains a collection of articles concerning nursing leaders such as Florence Nightingale, Linda Richards, Clara Louise Maass and Alice Fitzgerald are in the series. Copies of many brief biographies of nursing leaders (A - Z) can be found.
Series V: The International Council of Nurses (undated, 1925-1986) contains the correspondence of the prominent nurse Effie J. Taylor while she was president of the International Council of Nurses (ICN), 1937-1947. E. J. Taylor was a psychiatric nurse who promoted university based nursing education and served as the second dean of the Yale School of Nursing. She was president of ICNduring World War II and the difficulties she faced, including assisting with the immigration of the organization's executive secretary Anna Schwarzenberg, are described in her correspondence. In addition, E. J. Taylor's notes, articles and photographs are included.
Series VI: The National League of Nursing Committee on Historical Source Materials in Nursing (undated, 1955-1970) contains resource lists and minutes under presidents Martha E. Rogers and Josephine A. Dolan. The purpose of this committee was to locate historical resources in nursing and also to work toward a national nursing archive.
Series VII: Nursing Education (1871-1973) contains articles concerning nursing education, including a copy of the Goldmark Report (1923). These articles recount the struggle to establish nursing education in the university setting and to set higher standards for nursing education and practice.
Series VIII: Other Historical Materials (undated, 1871-1970), includes the National League of Nursing's general correspondence and 1970 officers' biographies, Connecticut Nursing Association articles, correspondence and by-laws, Frontier Nursing Service information (1954), and articles about the history of medicine and nursing.
Series IX: Josephine A. Dolan (undated, 1931-1993) contains the professor's correspondence regarding the acquisition of materials. In addition, J. A. Dolan's class syllabus and book review are included.
Series X: Extractions (1851-1980)contains publications from the Josephine A. Dolan collection.
Biography
Josephine A. Dolan was the first professor of nursing at the University of Connecticut School of Nursing>. She became interested in nursing history when she was given the class to teach in the nursing program. Miss Dolan collected materials to write a book on the history of nursing from dealers or, in the case of the Wolcott series, from descendants of the family. Miss Dolan died 13 December 2004.
Scope and Content
The records in this collection consist of materials gathered by the first nursing professor at the University of Connecticut School of Nursing, Josephine A. Dolan. The materials are primarily correspondence of the Wolcott family, articles and proceedings of various nursing organizations.
A considerable portion of the Wolcott Family correspondence has been digitized and is available online.
Separated Material
The following materials have been separated from the collection and cataloged:
Hopsital Notes Dodd WRT 24
Little Men Dodd A9763
Annual report of the National League of Nursing Education. (1918, 1920, 1932) Dodd Periodicals
Manual of Practice of Medicine. A8633
Nurses; History; College teachers; Nursing schools; United States (nation); Storrs (inhabited place); Connecticut (state); Correspondence; Manuscripts (document genre); Administrative records; Photographs; Publications (documents); Personal papers; Women; American Civil War (1861-1865); Nineteenth century; Military nursing--History; University of Connecticut. School of Nursing
- Series I: The Wolcott Collection, undated, 1833-1977
  - Wolcott family genealogy
    - New England Genealogy Register, 1847 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Henry Wolcott and His Children by Rev. S. Wolcott, 1859 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Memorial of Henry Wolcott, 1881 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Wolcott Genealogy of Ancient Windsor, CT, 1891 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Henry Wolcott Genealogy by Chandler Wolcott, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - British and American Wolcott Family, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Family Jottings by Roger Wolcott, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Toll-Wolcott, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Colonial Families of USA, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Magna Charta Sureties, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Handwritten Wolcott family trees, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Ancestral photographs, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - So. Windsor Wolcott homestead photograph, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Ella Louise Wolcott photographs, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Elmira, N.Y., E. L. Wolcott cottage photograph, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Beecher-Stowe family information and genealogy, undated, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Articles about Thomas Kinnicut Beecher, 1900-1924 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Kirby house plans, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Carter family photographs, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Lock of hair -? from Julia Wolcott Carter, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Julia Wolcott Carter autobiography (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Wolcott family reunion invitation, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Wolcott arms (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Berry Magna Charta Dames Certificate, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Katherine Wolcott Dwight Berry lineage, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence
    - Elihu Wolcott [?] and Hannah Kirby to Ella Louise Wolcott, 1848-1858 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Elihu Wolcott to son, 1833 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Elizur Wolcott family to E. L. Wolcott, 1848-1858 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Elizur Wolcott family to E. L. Wolcott, 1859-1897 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Julia Wolcott to E. L. Wolcott, 1840-1849 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Julia Wolcott Carter and husband, William Carter to, 1854-1859 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - E. L. Wolcott (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - E. L. Wolcott to J. W. and W. Carter; Carter family to E. L. Wolcott, 1860-1863; 1995-0028/SeriesI: WolcottCollection/Correspondence/Box2:18 (Box 2, Folder 18 [39153019939398])
      Wolcott, Ella L.
    - Carter family to E. L. Wolcott; E. L. Wolcott to Carter family, 1864-1869; 1995-0028/SeriesI: WolcottCollection/Correspondence/Box2:19 (Box 2, Folder 19 [39153019939406])
    - J. W. and W. Carter to E. L. Wolcott, 1870-1881; 1995-0028/SeriesI: WolcottCollection/Correspondence/Box2:20 (Box 2, Folder 20 [39153019939414])
    - J. W. and W. Carter to E. L. Wolcott, 1883-1889; 1995-0028/SeriesI: WolcottCollection/Correspondence/Box2:21 (Box 2, Folder 21 [39153019939422])
    - J. W. and W. Carter to E. L. Wolcott, 1890-1892; 1995-0028/SeriesI: WolcottCollection/Correspondence/Box2:22 (Box 2, Folder 22 [39153019939430])
    - J. W. and W. Carter to E. L. Wolcott, 1893-1896; 1995-0028/SeriesI: WolcottCollection/Correspondence/Box2:23 (Box 2, Folder 23 [39153019939448])
    - J. W. and W. Carter to E. L. Wolcott, 1897-1900; 1995-0028/SeriesI: WolcottCollection/Correspondence/Box2:24 (Box 2, Folder 24 [39153019939455])
    - J. W. and W. Carter to E. L. Wolcott, 1901-1904; 1995-0028/SeriesI: WolcottCollection/Correspondence/Box2:25 (Box 2, Folder 25 [39153019939463])
    - J. W. and W. Carter to E. L. Wolcott, 1905-1910; 1995-0028/SeriesI: WolcottCollection/Correspondence/Box2:26 (Box 2, Folder 26 [39153019939471])
    - Thomas Kinnicut Beecher to E. L. Wolcott, 1856-1863 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - T. K. Beecher to E. L. Wolcott, 1864-1865 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - E. L. Wolcott to T. K. and Julia Jones Beecher, 1862-1863 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - E. L. Wolcott to T. K. andJ. J. Beecher, 1864 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - E. L. Wolcott to T. K. and J. J. Beecher, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - C. A. Dana and Martha Wolcott to T. K. Beecher, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Beecher family to E. L. Wolcott, 1864-1900 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - E. L. Wolcott to Isabelle Hooker, undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - E. L. Wolcott and J. W. Carter to Helen Kirby Dwight, 1867-1901 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - E. L. Wolcott and J. W. Carter to H. K. Dwight, 1902-1910; 1995-0028/SeriesI: WolcottCollection/Correspondence/Box3:34 (Box 3, Folder 34 [39153019939042])
      Dwight, H. K.
    - Dwight family to E. L. Wolcott, 1866-1902; 1995-0028/SeriesI: WolcottCollection/Correspondence/Box3:35 (Box 3, Folder 35 [39153019939059])
    - Dwight family to E. L. Wolcott, 1904-1907; 1995-0028/SeriesI: WolcottCollection/Correspondence/Box3:36 (Box 3, Folder 36 [39153019939067])
    - Dwight family to E. L. Wolcott, 1908-1909; 1995-0028/SeriesI: WolcottCollection/Correspondence/Box3:37 (Box 3, Folder 37 [39153019939075])
    - Dwight family to E. L. Wolcott; E. L. Wolcott dictation to H. K. Dwight, 1910-1912; 1995-0028/SeriesI: WolcottCollection/Correspondence/Box3:38 (Box 3, Folder 38 [39153019939083])
      Wolcott, Ella L.; Dwight, H. K.
    - May Wolcott Clapp to H. K. Dwight, 1887-1913; 1995-0028/SeriesI: WolcottCollection/Correspondence/Box3:39 (Box 3, Folder 39 [39153019939091])
    - M. W. Clapp to H. K. Dwight, 1914-1923; 1995-0028/SeriesI: WolcottCollection/Correspondence/Box3:40 (Box 3, Folder 40 [39153019939109])
    - E. L. Wolcott to Hattie Foote Hawley, 1862-1869; 1995-0028/SeriesI: WolcottCollection/Correspondence/Box3:41 (Box 3, Folder 41)
      Hawley, Hattie Foote
    - Ernst Perabo to E. L. Wolcott and T. K. Beecher, 1869-1903; 1995-0028/SeriesI: WolcottCollection/Correspondence/Box3:42 (Box 3, Folder 42 [39153019939117])
      Wolcott, Ella L.; Beecher, T. K.
    - E. L. Wolcott's letters to and from friends, 1848-1904; 1995-0028/SeriesI: WolcottCollection/Correspondence/Box3:43 (Box 3, Folder 43 [39153019939125])
    - Mrs. J. H. Dumars to H. K. Dwight, 1908-1911; 1995-0028/SeriesI: WolcottCollection/Correspondence/Box3:44 (Box 3, Folder 44 [39153019939133])
    - Mrs. J. H. Dumars to H. K. Dwight, 1912; 1995-0028/SeriesI: WolcottCollection/Correspondence/Box3:45 (Box 3, Folder 45 [39153019939141])
    - E. L. Wolcott obituary and wills, 1892-1915; 1995-0028/SeriesI: WolcottCollection/Correspondence/Box3:46 (Box 3, Folder 46 [39153019939158])
    - Letters to H. K. Dwight regarding E. L. Wolcott estate; Thank you letters from Wolcott family to H. K. Dwight for E. L. Wolcott estate checks, 1915; 1995-0028/SeriesI: WolcottCollection/Correspondence/Box3:47 (Box 3, Folder 47 [39153019939166])
    - Letters regarding E. L. Wolcott estate, 1919-1942; 1995-0028/SeriesI: WolcottCollection/Correspondence/Box3:48 (Box 3, Folder 48 [39153019939224])
    - Other Wolcott family letters, 1849-1917; 1995-0028/SeriesI: WolcottCollection/Correspondence/Box3:49 (Box 3, Folder 49 [39153019939240])
  - Other Wolcott Papers
    - Articles by E. L. Wolcott, undated; 1995-0028/SeriesI: WolcottCollection/OtherWolcott/Box3:50 (Box 3, Folder 50 [39153019939232])
    - Photographs of Shakespeare Club (directed by E. L. Wolcott), undated; 1995-0028/SeriesI: WolcottCollection/OtherWolcott/Box3:51 (Box 3, Folder 51 [39153019939257])
    - Diaries of E. L. Wolcott, undated; 1995-0028/SeriesI: WolcottCollection/OtherWolcott/Box3:52 (Box 3, Folder 52 [39153019939265])
    - Creative works by E. L. Wolcott, 1846-1903; 1995-0028/SeriesI: WolcottCollection/OtherWolcott/Box4:53 (Box 4, Folder 53 [39153019939489])
    - Creative works by J. W. Carter and unknown authors, undated; 1995-0028/SeriesI: WolcottCollection/OtherWolcott/Box4:54 (Box 4, Folder 54 [39153019939281])
    - Literary clippings saved by E. L. Wolcott, undated; 1995-0028/SeriesI: WolcottCollection/OtherWolcott/Box4:55 (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Literary clippings saved by E. L. Wolcott, undated; 1995-0028/SeriesI: WolcottCollection/OtherWolcott/Box4:56 (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - E. L. Wolcott booklist, Blank postcard, psalm, Calendar, Musical program, undated, 1906, 1912; 1995-0028/SeriesI: WolcottCollection/OtherWolcott/Box4:57 (Box 4, Folder 57 [39153019939315])
    - Letter unknown author and recipient, Proposal of marriage, unknown author and recipient, undated; 1995-0028/SeriesI: WolcottCollection/OtherWolcott/Box4:58 (Box 4, Folder 58 [39153019939323])
- Series II: Wartime Nursing, undated, 1843-1901
  - Civil War papers
    - E. L. Wolcott correspondence, 1862-1863; 1995-0028/SeriesII:WartimeNursing/CW/Box4:59 (Box 4, Folder 59 [39153019939554])
    - E. L. Wolcott correspondence with Dorothea L. Dix and others, 1863-1865; 1995-0028/SeriesII:WartimeNursing/CW/Box4:60 (Box 4, Folder 60 [39153019939562])
      Dix, Dorothea Lynde, 1802-1887; Wolcott, Ella L.
    - Supply lists and muster rolls, 1863-1865; 1995-0028/SeriesII:WartimeNursing/CW/Box4:61 (Box 4, Folder 61 [39153019939570])
    - Diet lists by E. L. Wolcott, undated; 1995-0028/SeriesII:WartimeNursing/CW/Box9:62 (Box 9, Folder 62 [39153013988912])
    - Theater program, patron list, 1865; 1995-0028/SeriesII:WartimeNursing/CW/Box4:63 (Box 9, Folder 63 [39153013989076])
    - E. L. Wolcott correspondence about the Civil War from D. L. Dix and others, 1865-1867; 1995-0028/SeriesII:WartimeNursing/CW/Box4:64 (Box 4, Folder 64 [39153019939604])
    - E. L. Wolcott correspondence about the Civil War from Dorothea L. Dix and others, 1868-1871; 1995-0028/SeriesII:WartimeNursing/CW/Box4:65 (Box 4, Folder 65 [39153019939612])
    - Selected Letters from Civil War Correspondence of Miss Ella L. Wolcott ed. by Marion Dwight, 1856-1862; 1995-0028/SeriesII:WartimeNursing/CW/Box4:66 (Box 4, Folder 66 [39153019939620])
      Wolcott, Ella L.; Dwight, Marion
    - Selected Letters from Civil War Correspondence of Miss Ella L. Wolcott ed. by Marion Dwight, 1863; 1995-0028/SeriesII:WartimeNursing/CW/Box4:67 (Box 4, Folder 67 [39153019939638])
      Dwight, Marion; Wolcott, Ella L.
    - Selected Letters from Civil War Correspondence of Miss Ella L. Wolcott ed. by Marion Dwight, 1864; 1995-0028/SeriesII:WartimeNursing/CW/Box4:68 (Box 4, Folder 68 [39153019939646])
    - Selected Letters from Civil War Correspondence of Miss Ella L. Wolcott ed. by Marion Dwight, 1865; 1995-0028/SeriesII:WartimeNursing/CW/Box4:69 (Box 4, Folder 69 [39153019939653])
    - Memorial by D. L. Dix to theMassachusetts legislature, 1843 (Box 5, Folder 70)
    - Correspondence of Harriet Eaton, Civil War Nurse, 1862-1901 (Box 5, Folder 71)
  - War Related Material
    - Nursing photographs during war (Civil War, WWI, Army Nurse Corps), undated (Box 5, Folder 72)
    - Articles about wartime nursing, WWII nursing and Cadet Nurse Corps, undated (Box 5, Folder 73)
    - American Red Cross articles, history, correspondence, undated (Box 5, Folder 74)
- Series III: Nursing Schools and Organizations, undated, 1873-1978
  - American Society of Superintendents of Training Schools for Nurses annual conventions 1-3, 1894-1896 (Box 5, Folder 75)
  - American Society of Superintendents of Training Schools for Nurses annual conventions 4-7, 1897-1900 (Box 5, Folder 76)
  - Bellevue School of Nursing historical articles, photographs, undated, 1942-1963 (Box 5, Folder 77)
  - Boston Training School historical articles, 1902-1948 (Box 5, Folder 78)
  - Philadelphia General Hospital School of Nursing Blockley Division historical articles, 1951-1978 (Box 5, Folder 79)
  - Philadelphia General Hospital School of Nursing Blockley Division photos, pamphlets, undated, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 80)
  - Connecticut Training School historical articles, 1873-1925 (Box 5, Folder 81)
  - Connecticut Training School historical articles and photographs, 1926-1943 (Box 5, Folder 82)
  - Connecticut Training School Alumni Association correspondence and papers, 1902-1956 (Box 6, Folder 83)
  - Connecticut Training School Alumni Association correspondence and papers, 1957-1961 (Box 6, Folder 84)
  - Connecticut Training School Alumni Association correspondence and papers, 1962-1964 (Box 6, Folder 85)
  - Connecticut Training School Alumni Association financial correspondence, 1947-1963 (Box 6, Folder 86)
- Series IV: Nursing Leaders, 1867-1995
  - Florence Nightingale historical articles, 1867-1920 (Box 6, Folder 87)
  - Florence Nightingale historical articles, 1937-1976 (Box 6, Folder 88)
  - Kaiserswerth and the Fliedners, 1961-1970 (Box 6, Folder 89)
  - Photographs of the Nightingales, undated (Box 6, Folder 90)
  - Linda Richards historical articles, 1901-1948 (Box 6, Folder 91)
  - Clara Louise Maass historical articles, photographs, 1899-1976 (Box 6, Folder 92)
  - Alice Fitzgerald, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 93)
  - Biographies of nursing leaders, A - Z, 1942-1995 (Box 7, Folder 94)
- Series V: International Council of Nurses, undated, 1925-1986
  - Correspondence
    - Effie J. Taylor, Pres. correspondence, 1935-1938 (Box 7, Folder 95)
    - Effie J. Taylor, Pres. correspondence, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 96)
    - Effie J. Taylor, Pres. correspondence, 1940-1949 (Box 7, Folder 97)
    - Exec. Secr. Anna Schwarzenberg's immigration, 1939-1940 (Box 7, Folder 98)
    - Exec. Secr. Anna Schwarzenberg's immigration, 1941-1943 (Box 7, Folder 99)
  - Effie J. Taylor Papers
    - Notes, addresses, 1925-1939 (Box 7, Folder 100)
    - Notes, addresses, 1940-1947 (Box 7, Folder 101)
    - Other letters and articles, 1938-1948 (Box 7, Folder 102)
    - Articles about E. J. Taylor and awards received, 1940-1986 (Box 7, Folder 103)
    - E. J. Taylor photographs, undated (Box 7, Folder 104)
- Series VI: The National League of Nursing Committee on Historical Source Materials in Nursing, undated, 1955-1970
  - Identified resource lists, undated (Box 7, Folder 105)
  - Identified resource lists, undated (Box 7, Folder 106)
  - Committee minutes, 1955-1956 (Box 7, Folder 107)
  - Committee minutes, 1957-1958 (Box 7, Folder 108)
  - Committee minutes, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 109)
  - Committee minutes, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 110)
  - Committee minutes, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 111)
  - Committee minutes, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 112)
  - Committee minutes, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 113)
  - Committee minutes, 1964-1965 (Box 7, Folder 114)
  - Committee minutes, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 115)
  - Committee minutes, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 116)
  - Committee minutes, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 117)
  - Committee minutes, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 118)
  - Committee minutes, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 119)
- Series VII: Nursing Education, 1871-1973
  - National Commission for the Study of Nursing and Nursing Education, 1970-1973 (Box 7, Folder 120)
  - Nursing education articles, 1871-1960 (Box 7, Folder 121)
  - Goldmark Report, 1920
- Series VIII: Other Historical Materials, undated, 1871-1970
  - National League for Nursing correspondence, 1915-1973 (Box 7, Folder 122)
  - Biographies of officers, 1970
  - Connecticut Nurses' Association by-laws, letters, undated (Box 7, Folder 123)
  - American Nurses' Association press releases, 1948
  - Frontier Nursing Service information, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 124)
  - History of medicine articles, 1933-1968 (Box 7, Folder 125)
  - Nursing history articles, 1871-1954 (Box 7, Folder 126)
- Series IX: Josephine A. Dolan, undated, 1931-1993
  - Correspondence regarding collection of materials, 1966-1979 (Box 7, Folder 127)
  - Class syllabus, book reviews, 1964, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 128)
  - Newspaper articles, 1944-1993 (Box 7, Folder 129)
  - Dolan Awards, 1972-1993 (Box 7, Folder 130)
  - Correspondence—Professional, 1944-1983 (Box 7, Folder 131)
  - Academic Transcripts, 1931-1942 (Box 7, Folder 132)
  - Academic Diplomas and Degrees, 1942-1987 (Box 7, Folder 133)
  - Certificates and Licenses, undated (Box 7, Folder 134)
  - Photographs, 1931-1987 (Box 7, Folder 135)
  - Publications, 1950-1975 (Box 7, Folder 136)
  - Professional Activities, 1952-1988 (Box 7, Folder 137)
  - Professional Memorabilia, 1979-1992 (Box 7, Folder 138-141)
- Series X: Extractions, 1851-1980 (Box 8)
  - Adelaide Nutting Historical Nursing Collection Teachers College Columbia University. New York: McAuliffe & Booth.., (1929)
  - American History Illustrated (Eds.). The concise illustrated history of the Civil War, 6(2). Natural Historical Society Publication., (1971).
  - American Journal of Nursing. "Edith P. Lewis on nursing." Philip E. Day, Publisher., (1980).
  - American Nurses' Association. The continuing search for meaning. New York: American Nurses' Association, (1964).
  - American Red Cross. American Red Cross Nursing Services, (1961).
  - Bellevue Bulletin 71(1), 1966.
  - Bellevue Bulletin 71(2), 1966.
  - Bellevue Bulletin 72(1), 1967.
  - Bellevue Bulletin 72(2), 1967.
  - Bellevue Bulletin 73(1), 1968.
  - Bellevue Bulletin 73(2), 1968.
  - Bellevue Bulletin 74(1), 1969.
  - Bellevue Bulletin 74(2), 1969.
  - Bellevue Bulletin 75(1), 1970.
  - Bellevue Bulletin 75(2), 1970.
  - Bellevue Bulletin 76(2), 1972.
  - Bellevue Bulletin 78(1), 1973.